<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vb on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://im5tu.io/tags/vb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vb on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 12:15:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/tags/vb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenMessage 2017 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2017/02/openmessage-2017-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 12:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2017/02/openmessage-2017-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/im5tu/openmessage&#34;&gt;OpenMessage&lt;/a&gt; originally started out as a replacement for an internal library that was used across teams. At the time, the team I was apart of needed the latest version of dotnet core for the library where as the other team were stuck on RC1. They were also developing features for that version of the framework and a few pre-existing details that we were unhappy with (eg: the request/response implementation). With that in mind, I created a minimal wrapper for what we needed. Looking forward, I plan to dedicate a bit more time to the project and improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenMessage 1.1 Released</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2017/02/openmessage-1.1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 15:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2017/02/openmessage-1.1-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick update to say that the Azure provider for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Im5tu/OpenMessage&#34;&gt;OpenMessage&lt;/a&gt; has been released. This update fixes an issue with scheduling messages on topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semaphore vs SeamphoreSlim Micro Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2013/03/semaphore-vs-seamphoreslim-micro-benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 18:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2013/03/semaphore-vs-seamphoreslim-micro-benchmark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to show a small micro-benchmark to demonstrate the performance difference between the &lt;code&gt;Semaphore&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;SemaphoreSlim&lt;/code&gt; classes in C#. A &lt;code&gt;Semaphore&lt;/code&gt; is often used to restrict the number of threads than can access some (physical or logical) resource. In this case, we want the restriction to be as little as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flicker free forms and listview in .Net</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2012/12/flicker-free-forms-and-listview-in-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 14:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2012/12/flicker-free-forms-and-listview-in-.net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a project I have been working on recently, I came across a problem where under Windows an Mdi Child form would flicker when it loads. Trying to find information on what was the cause of this was near impossible. I ended up trying a lot of code snippets that I found when googling the problem and this is what I have come up with.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension methods in dotnet</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2012/12/extension-methods-in-dotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 17:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2012/12/extension-methods-in-dotnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article we will take a look at what extension methods are and how to use them in .Net. Personally, they are one of the best things that has been introduced into the .Net framework in terms of readability. I will take you through what extension methods are, how to create them (in c# and vb) then I will show you some of the extension methods that I have created (in c# only, conversion is for you to try).
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>