<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devlunch on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://im5tu.io/tags/devlunch/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devlunch on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/tags/devlunch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Lunches: What, Why, How</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2014/12/dev-lunches-what-why-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 18:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2014/12/dev-lunches-what-why-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not up-to-date, you fall behind. You fall behind in your work, which leads you to fall behind at home. If continued, it&amp;rsquo;s a never ending circle that can seem like climbing Everest in order to overcome. I propose that we, as developers, start doing is utilizing our free time to help not only ourselves but our co-workers too. We can do this via dev lunches.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-is-a-dev-lunch&#34;&gt;So what is a dev lunch?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dev lunch, or developers lunch, is based upon the idea of sacrificing an hours lunch on a specific topic or topics, much like a mini-conference for you and your co-workers. Topics can range for technical deep dives to non-technical, team-wide talks such as &amp;ldquo;What does it mean to be Agile?&amp;rdquo;. The format is typically manifests as one of two styles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-talks&#34;&gt;Single talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a single talk, a developer will take the topic in hand, research the subject and present it to the attendees. The talk will typically last about 30-40 minutes leaving time for Q&amp;amp;A etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lightning-talks&#34;&gt;Lightning talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks take the form of a series of individuals from the team presenting for x time on a range of subjects. X is usually around 5-10 minutes. The subjects can be related, or completely unrelated. Essentially, they are multiple, compressed single talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to remember that the topics are chosen by the presenter themselves. The presenter may ask for ideas/feedback from the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-invest-in-dev-lunches&#34;&gt;Why invest in dev lunches?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the benefits from the developer and business perspectives are pretty much the same:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge is shared throughout the team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be used as a sort of team bonding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourages the use of soft skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-get-started&#34;&gt;How do I get started?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, you&amp;rsquo;ve read up until here so the idea is already in your mind. In terms of setting up the event, pick a date/time about &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; weeks in the future to give you time to prepare and allow people to keep that hour free. Then you can have a think of an idea like those listed at the bottom of the page. Once you have that sorted, simply send out a meeting request (or similar) letting people know what you are doing, when and where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentations don&amp;rsquo;t have to be anything too fancy, just something on &lt;a href=&#34;http://slid.es&#34;&gt;Slid.es&lt;/a&gt; or Powerpoint will be fine. Just make sure that it is easily readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to talk to your boss and let them know what you are doing. On the off chance see if there is a chance of free food, you never know right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already started this movement at two places I have worked and received exceptional feedback. So I encourage you to try and sort this at your workplace and see if it can help you become better. Here are a couple of tips from my experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert, so don&amp;rsquo;t try and become one overnight,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if things go wrong, the attendees are your friends and can help,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t pick a topic that is a) no interest to you, it will come off in your presentation; and b) too big, you will end up speed talking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do remember to have fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;list-of-starter-ideas&#34;&gt;List of starter ideas&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these topics, explore the title trying to think of what/why/how&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principals of SOLID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dependency Injection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grunt Tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does it mean to be Agile?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;speaker-resources&#34;&gt;Speaker Resources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/speaking/&#34;&gt;http://www.hanselman.com/speaking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zachholman.com/talk/the-talk-on-talks/&#34;&gt;Talk on Talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>