<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Building a blog on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://im5tu.io/categories/building-a-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Building a blog on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 20:25:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/categories/building-a-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Quick Tip: Inlining Css Files</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/12/hugo-quick-tip-inlining-css-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 20:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/12/hugo-quick-tip-inlining-css-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I have been doing a little bit of work on my site and one of the things that I wanted to do is inline the css file. It&#39;s quite a small file anyway, and once compressed with gzip should make a fairly minimal difference to the size of the page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Building - Part 4 - Frontend</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-4-frontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 08:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-4-frontend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far we have built a very basic site and got a basic understanding of how to configure and override the theme. Next up we are going to configure our frontend workflow using yarn and gulp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Building - Part 3 - Theming</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-3-theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 19:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-3-theming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will show you how the theme has been constructed and show you how the overrides work. So far we have created a site, setup most of our workflow and posted our first article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Building - Part 2 - My First Post</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-2-my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 23:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-2-my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building---part-1---hello-hugo/&#34;&gt;the last article&lt;/a&gt;, we setup our workflow and all the pieces that you will need to create a new site. Now we need to install a theme and begin publishing. Prior to writing this series, I began evaluating the extensibility of hugo themes and started work on something I call bones - a no thrills template with no styling, just structure. As I improve the template it will become more useful, maybe. It will remain the template behind mysite as I continue to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Building - Part 1 - Hello Hugo</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-1-hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-1-hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As promised in this first mini-series, I am going to guide you through the steps that I have taken to get my blog up and running on Github pages and Cloudflare with SSL. As these the steps that I have taken to get this blog up and running, your milage may vary with this as different versions get released. That said, you should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 19:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World. Safe to say it&#39;s been a little while since I have blogged or even had a website come to think of it. Alas, I am back with some fresh ideas and recharged to help you dear reader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>