<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building A Blog With Hugo on Stuart Blackler's Blog</title><link>https://im5tu.io/series/building-a-blog-with-hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Building A Blog With Hugo on Stuart Blackler's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 08:01:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/series/building-a-blog-with-hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog Building - Part 4 - Frontend</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-4-frontend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 08:01:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-4-frontend/</guid><description>&lt;p>So far we have built a very basic site and got a basic understanding of how to configure and override the theme. Next up we are going to configure our frontend workflow using yarn and gulp.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog Building - Part 3 - Theming</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-3-theming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 19:01:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-3-theming/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this article, I will show you how the theme has been constructed and show you how the overrides work. So far we have created a site, setup most of our workflow and posted our first article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog Building - Part 2 - My First Post</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-2-my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 23:01:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-2-my-first-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building---part-1---hello-hugo/">the last article&lt;/a>, we setup our workflow and all the pieces that you will need to create a new site. Now we need to install a theme and begin publishing. Prior to writing this series, I began evaluating the extensibility of hugo themes and started work on something I call bones - a no thrills template with no styling, just structure. As I improve the template it will become more useful, maybe. It will remain the template behind mysite as I continue to improve it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog Building - Part 1 - Hello Hugo</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-1-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-1-hello-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>As promised in this first mini-series, I am going to guide you through the steps that I have taken to get my blog up and running on Github pages and Cloudflare with SSL. As these the steps that I have taken to get this blog up and running, your milage may vary with this as different versions get released. That said, you should be fine.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>