<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fitness on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://im5tu.io/categories/fitness/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fitness on Stuart Blackler&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/categories/fitness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2017</title>
      <link>https://im5tu.io/article/2017/01/my-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 13:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2017/01/my-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about writing this post for a little while now, but never seem to get around to it. I know that I&amp;rsquo;m massively late to the 2017 blog post party, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think about it for quite a while. I wanted to refocus and find out what I really wanted to achieve rather than a token guesture that would likely fail like previously. I&amp;rsquo;ve split this out into two main categories below: Personal and Professional Development.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-development&#34;&gt;Personal Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;health-fitness&#34;&gt;Health &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my primary goal for 2017. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest and say that 2015 &amp;amp; 2016 wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly the greatest for me. So much so, I acquired the name &amp;ldquo;the feeder&amp;rdquo; at my previous job. I was always eating. As we all know, eating &amp;amp; a sedentary job means weight gain. I topped out at 106kg approximately. For me, as a former athlete, this was massive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting off just after Christmas, I purchased both a Fitbit Charge 2 and the Fitbit Aria to begin my transformation (I&amp;rsquo;ll post my thoughts on these products soon). I am tracking as much data as I can including water/food consumption, weight/body fat and mood. With all the data, I hope to make small adjustments (heklo agile!) rather than big shocking changes that i&amp;rsquo;ve previously made. Exercise is not the biggest part of this, it&amp;rsquo;s the nutrional side. So far this month, I have seen a big change. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been as on plan as I would have liked, but I am correcting this day by day and trying to make healthier choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;linguistics&#34;&gt;Linguistics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the goal of linguistics falls into two parts: writing and foreign languages. As I blog more throughout the year, I know that my writing will naturally improve as and when I get feedback on posts. As I begin to read more books, i&amp;rsquo;ll learn new and exciting words/phrases that will aid with this also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a British person, I am always amazed everytime that I travel to a different country. Nearly everyone seems to be able to speak English, but we (myself included) cannot return the pleasantaries. So for this aim, i&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded and began using an app called Duolingo to begin learning Dutch. Why Dutch? I seem to be there every year now for dance events so it would be nice to speak the language as to not be so ignorant when I travel. I&amp;rsquo;m off there again next month, so I highly doubt i&amp;rsquo;ll be able to say anything useful, but i&amp;rsquo;m putting in a solid shift with the aim of being able to order some food in Dutch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mentality&#34;&gt;Mentality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above two goals require a strong mindset as there will be the enevitible ups and downs. For this, I have taken inspiration from the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jockowillink&#34;&gt;Jocko Willink&lt;/a&gt;. Jocko is co-author of a book called Extreme Ownership and hosts his own podcast. The podcast is what has been the primary driver behind the changes that I am making. One particular aspect that I liked is when Jocko was talking about a person failing in a situation when he was in the seal teams, to which he responded with &amp;ldquo;Good!&amp;rdquo;. Why good? Well, out of every bad situation comes a chance to learn and progress not only yourselves, but potentially others. Taking a positive spin on everything can only be a good thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional-development&#34;&gt;Professional Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;social&#34;&gt;Social&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fail at this level in so many ways. If I can just be consistent with getting back to people on LinkedIn, writing more consistently and posting relevant, interesting content then I would be happy. I used to think that blogging was only about writing long technical articles, but there is so much more than that. I hope to open up about what i&amp;rsquo;m doing both technical and non-technical in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After changing my job role towards the back end of last year, I will be looking at consolidating my position and growing within the role. It&amp;rsquo;s my first senior role, so I am getting used to the additional responsibilities that it brings. Moreover, I have transferred from the telecommunications industry to creative. Personally, I think getting a broad set of industry experience is crucial for developers as each industry will present different challenges. It&amp;rsquo;s also my first time working with a CMS system. Coming from a non-CMS background, some quirks have definitely caught me by surprise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that wraps up what I imagine 2017 to be like for me. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep myself accountable by posting regular updates on social media and here on the blog every few months. Thanks for reading, see you again soon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>