<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>git on Stuart Blackler's Blog</title><link>https://im5tu.io/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in git on Stuart Blackler's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 12:56:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Favourite Git Aliases</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2020/07/my-favourite-git-aliases/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 12:56:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2020/07/my-favourite-git-aliases/</guid><description>&lt;p>Git aliases are used to create new git commands that can either invoke a function, or be used to create commands that map to longer commands. For example, we could map &lt;code>git co&lt;/code> to &lt;code>git checkout&lt;/code> or have &lt;code>git undo&lt;/code> undo our previous commit. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you some of my favourite git aliases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog Building - Part 1 - Hello Hugo</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-1-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2016/11/blog-building-part-1-hello-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>As promised in this first mini-series, I am going to guide you through the steps that I have taken to get my blog up and running on Github pages and Cloudflare with SSL. As these the steps that I have taken to get this blog up and running, your milage may vary with this as different versions get released. That said, you should be fine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Up And Running With Git And Powershell</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2015/02/up-and-running-with-git-and-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 18:37:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2015/02/up-and-running-with-git-and-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve all experienced a time where we use our pc&amp;rsquo;s for a prolonged period of time, accumulating a ton of crap along the way as we try out various technologies and fads. After a while, the pc begins to do funny things like crash for no apparent reason. This week, I needed to rebuild my dev machine and decided to change from Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s Source Tree over to Powershell and raw git.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>